mccall.com 2011-12-09

# Privacy Policy | McCall's Patterns

Effective September 16, 2011

The McCall Pattern Company (“McCall Pattern or “We”) is committed to protecting the privacy of our visitors while they interact with the content, products and services on our websites (the “Sites”).  This Privacy Policy applies to the Sites only and does not apply to other websites to which we link.  Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we want you to understand what information we collect about you, how we collect it, how that information is used, and how you can control our disclosure of it. You agree that your use of the Sites signifies your assent to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Sites.

###### 1.              Information Collected

We collect three types of information from you: i) information that you provide to us (e.g. through a voluntary registration process, sign-ups or emails); ii) information we collect or receive from others; and iii) information that is derived through automated tracking mechanisms and technology.

We collect personally identifiable information when you choose to use certain features of the Sites, including but not limited to: i) consenting to receive email messages about upcoming promotions or events, ii) consenting to receive email, and iii) commenting on articles, and others.   This information may include your name, postal address, email address, and telephone number.  We may also collect other types of information such as your gender, age, and personal interests, which we may associate with personally identifiable information.  If you purchase products or services from us, we may collect, for example, credit card information, the type of services or products ordered or purchased, and the date of the order or purchase.  You may also provide us with written materials, photographs or other materials, which may contain personal information.  We may collect personal information when you register on, log on, or visit our Sites, including when you participate in activities on our Sites, such as contests, games, and informational and promotional offers, if any, and when you provide information to our customer service representatives.  Further, our Sites may offer message boards, chat rooms, and other public forums, as well as other features in which you may provide us with user submissions.  If you provide personal information when you use any of these features, that personal information may be publicly posted and otherwise disclosed without limitation as to its use by a third party.

We may update and supplement personally identifiable information that we have collected directly from you with other information that we obtain from third parties.  In addition, we may obtain personally identifiable information about individuals who are not yet users of our Sites.  When we associate information that we obtain from third parties with personally identifiable information that we have collected under this Privacy Policy, we will treat the acquired information in the same way we treat the information that we collected ourselves and, except as permitted by this Privacy Policy, the information will not be shared with third parties.

We collect information through automated tracking mechanisms and technology to make our Sites more interesting and useful to you and for various purposes related to our business.   For instance, when you come to our Sites, we collect your IP address.  An IP address is associated with the access point through which you enter the Internet, and is typically controlled by your Internet Service Provider (ISP), your company, or your university.   On its own, your IP address is not personally identifiable.  We may use IP addresses to collect information regarding the frequency with which visitors to our Sites visit various parts of our sites, and we may combine IP addresses with personally identifiable information.  We also use "cookies" and other tracking technologies.  Cookies enable us to serve secure pages to our users without asking them to sign in repeatedly.  Most browsers allow you to control cookies, including whether or not to accept them and how to remove them.

You may set most browsers to notify you if you receive a cookie, or you may choose to block cookies with your browser, but please note that if you choose to erase or block your cookies, you will need to re-enter your original user ID and password to gain access to certain parts of the Sites.

###### 2.              How We Use Your Information

Except as set forth herein, McCall Pattern will not disclose, use, give or sell any personal information to third parties for any purposes other than to our suppliers and other third parties (who may use such information in order to deliver products and services on our behalf) or unless required to do so by law.  We reserve the right to contact you regarding matters relevant to the underlying service provided and/or the information collected.  From time to time, we may use, give or sell, without further notification to you, any personal information to third parties who may use such information in order to deliver any products and services to you.

We may permit certain trusted third parties to track usage, analyze data such as the source address that a page request is coming from, your IP address or domain name, the date and time of the page request, the referring web site (if any) and other parameters in the URL. This is collected in order to better understand our web site usage, and enhance the performance of services to maintain and operate the Sites and certain features on the Sites. We may use third parties to host the Sites; operate various features available on the Sites; send emails; analyze data; provide search results and links.

Also, we may share personally identifiable or other information with our parent, subsidiaries, divisions, affiliates, consultants, contractors and sub-contractors.

We may transfer personally identifiable information as an asset in connection with a proposed or actual merger or sale (including any transfers made as part of an insolvency or bankruptcy proceeding) involving all or part of our business or as part of a corporate reorganization, stock sale or other change in control.

McCall Pattern may disclose personally identifiable information in special cases where we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating our terms and conditions of use or may be causing injury or interference with our rights, property, our customers or anyone who could be harmed by such activities.

WE ARE NOT LIABLE OR RESPONSIBLE FOR THE PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE OR OTHER INFORMATION YOU CHOOSE TO SUBMIT IN FORUMS SUCH AS A COMMENT AREA OR ANY OTHER PUBLICLY ACCESSIBLE AREA OF THE SITE, IF ANY.

We use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design our website and for business and administrative purposes. We may also use or share with third parties for any purpose aggregated data that contains no personally identifiable information.

###### 3.              How We Protect Your Information

We are committed to protecting the information we receive from you. We take appropriate security measures to protect your information against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we maintain appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information and data stored on our system. While no computer system is completely secure, we believe the measures we have implemented reduce the likelihood of security problems to a level appropriate to the type of data involved.

We are compliant with the Payment Card Industry (“PCI”) requirements.

###### 4.              Accessing & Updating Your Personal Information & Preferences

We provide mechanisms for updating and correcting your personal information for many of our services.  If you are a registered user, you may access and update your registration information and your preferences to receive email or other communications from us in the account area or by sending an email to [accountservices@mccall.com](mailto:accountservices@mccall.com).

###### 5.              Email Choice/Opt-out

If any user who receives an email from the Sites would prefer not to receive such communications in the future, he or she can do so by following the instructions in the emails.  We will make commercially reasonable efforts to implement your opt-out requests promptly, but you may still receive communications from us for up to ten business days as we process your request.

###### 6.              Children’s Privacy & Parental Controls

We do not solicit any personal information from children. If you are not 13 or older, you are not authorized to use the Sites. Parents should be aware that there are parental control tools available online that can be used to prevent children from submitting information online without parental permission or from accessing material that is harmful to minors.

###### 7.              Disclaimer to Security

By consenting to the [Terms of Use](http://mccallpattern.mccall.com/terms-of-use-pages-2762.php) of the Sites and the Privacy Policy, you consent that no data transmission over the Internet is completely secure. We cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you provide to us and you transmit such information to us at your own risk.

###### 8.              Notification of Changes To This Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time at our sole discretion. If we amend this Privacy Policy to permit material changes in the way we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will notify you of such amendment by sending you an email at the last email address that you provided us, and/or by posting notice of the amendment on our Sites.  Any such amendment to this Privacy Policy will be effective immediately after we post notice of the changes on the Sites. Your use of the Sites indicates your assent to the Privacy Policy as posted, and your continued use of the Sites after amendments have been posted will constitute acceptance of, and agreement to be bound by, those amendments.

You are responsible at all times for updating your personal information and  providing us with your current email address.  In the event that the last email address you have provided us is not valid, or for any other reason is not capable of delivering to you the notice described above, our dispatch of the email containing such notice will nonetheless constitute effective notice of the amendment described in the notice.  In any event, an amendment to this Privacy Policy may permit material changes in the way we use and share personal information that you provided us prior to our notification to you of such amendment. If you do not wish to allow such material changes, you must so notify us (in the manner we specify) prior to the effective date of the amendment. If you send us this notice, we may choose to deactivate your account.  Please be advised, however, that, regardless of whether you provide such notice to us, any such amendment to this Privacy Policy will apply to any personal information that you provide to us on or after the effective date of such amendment.

###### 9.              Contact Information

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices please contact us at [privacy@mccall.com](mailto:privacy@mccall.com).
